Omar Almalol

Tripoli, Tripoli, Libya



omar.alma3lol@gmail.com



+218913602170



linkedin.com/in/omaralmalol

Summary

Software architect, Full-stack dev, MERN stack specialist.

Expert in Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices & Cloud-based deployment.

Unit-testing, CI/CD & all DevOps aspects are essentials to me.

Creator of RepresentJS: https://github.com/alma3lol/representjs

I train devs, rewrite legacy code to meet modern demands, ensure quality in code using TDD and design patterns.

Professional team player, strong analytical, problem solving, excellent communication skills, team leader.

Kind of a perfectionist, but pragmatic enough to know when it's done.

Stuff I use:

- MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Firebase, MSSQL, Neo4j.
- Laravel, NodeJS, ExpressJS, LoopBack 4.
- React, Redux, Vue, Vuex, Sass.
- Java (incl: Android).
- SOLID principles, Concept of Web Components, Clean-code, Functional Reactive Programming, TDD.
- Git/Git-flow.
- MVC, MVI, MVVM architectures.
- UX/UI, Responsive design.
- GOF design patterns (Singleton, Facade, Mediator, ...etc).
- Agile's methodologies, Scrum.

Check out my GitHub profile: https://github.com/alma3lol/

Experience



🚀 Full Stack Developer

Freelancer

Mar 2018 - Present (5 years)

Full Stack Web Developer.

React, Redux, Sass, Node.js, WebSockets, webpack, Babel, JSX, etc.

Programmer

None

May 2008 - Present (14 years 10 months)

I first started programming in the age of 14 using Visual Basic 6 programming language.

Then started using VB.NET on 2010 and 2012 was the beginning of PHP career.

Full Stack developer

Lamah Technologies

Aug 2020 - May 2021 (10 months)

Technical Trainer

Moomken Organization

Mar 2021 - Mar 2021 (1 month)

I trained people in software engineering for 3 weeks.

Devsly Frontend Web Developer

Devsly

Dec 2020 - Mar 2021 (4 months)

I'm responsible for build frontend apps with high quality

■ Web Development Team Lead

Sahabah

Feb 2020 - Aug 2020 (7 months)

■ MERN-stack developer

Sahabah

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020 (8 months)

Tutor

Alnajem Almoneer

May 2019 - Oct 2019 (6 months)

PHP Developer

Mowa'ma

Nov 2017 - Apr 2019 (1 year 6 months)

PHP developer

Full Stack Web Developer

TechLines for Telecom and Information Technology LLC

Dec 2018 - Dec 2018 (1 month)

Full Stack Web Developer.

Android Developer

Masarat.ly

Jul 2018 - Jul 2018 (1 month)

Education



Kingston English Acadimy

Acadimic student, English 2015 - 2015

I've been taught on the hands of one of the best teachers that I ever had, Mrs. Nadiye Celik. She's an excellent teacher, she taught me that the first thing to learn a language is to read a lot. "The more you read, the more you speak and write" she said. She always said that, but I had a different opinion. "The more you listen to the language being spoken, the more you'll be able to read, write and speak". And she agreed on that, so she decided to start making debates in the class room and in activities, and here I am. The more I listened the more my English improved.

Licenses & Certifications



in Advanced Product Marketing - LinkedIn



in Learning Data Governance - LinkedIn

Skills

UX • TDD • React.js • Web Development • Unit Testing • UI • Agile Methodologies • Agile Project Management • Scrum • Troubleshooting